But that's absolute nonsense.
这绝对是胡说
Look, we didn't want to be on this ship. It was an accident.
是这样, 我们并不想到这艘船上来的, 是一次事故
You said you were passengers.
你刚说你们是乘客
I was merely trying to avoid a lot of tiresome explanations, old chap.
我只是想把事情弄简单一点, 免得浪费半天口舌, 老伙计
Stewart, I'll leave Kemp on board to take your ship back to Earth.
Stewart, 我把 Kemp 留在船上, 带你们回地球
What about these two?
这两个人怎么办?
Lock them in the hold, put a guard on them.
把他们所进置留室, 派人看着他们
- But we haven't done anything. - They say you have. Take them away.
- 但我们没干过任何事啊 - 他们说你干过. 带走
Now, if you'll only listen to me...
诶, 如果你能听我说...
You can talk to Earth Security.
你跟地球安全部去说吧
They'll listen, it's their business.
他们会听的, 这是他们的工作
- Put them in the starboard cubicle. - All right, get moving.
- 把他们带到右舷小隔间去 - 好的, 走
In there.
进去
Oops. No need to push.
噢, 没必要推啊
Doctor, well, now the Ogrons have gone,
博士, 对了, 既然 Ograns 已经走了
why don't the crewmen remember what really happened?
为什么这些船员还是想不起来真正发生了什么?
Because the true facts have been erased from their minds, that's why.
因为真相已经从他们大脑里面抹掉了, 这就是为什么
Well, yes, but why did they keep telling lies about us?
哦, 这样, 但为什么他们又一直说胡说八道呢?
Oh, they don't know that they're lying, Jo.
哦, 他们并不知道他们在胡说八道, Jo
They're desperately trying to fit us into their version of things.
他们只是在尽力地把我们装进他们那个版本的真实中去
Well, what are we going to do then?
那, 我们该怎么办?
Well, when we get back to Earth,
现在, 等我们回到地球
we've got to reach someone in authority
whose mind isn't already closed.
我们应该能碰到某个当权者, 他的大脑没有那么封闭?
Closed to what?
封闭?
Jo, look, these people believe
Jo, 你看, 这些人相信
that the Draconians are attacking their spaceships, right?
是龙族人袭击了他们的飞船, 对吧?
- Right. - We know that they're wrong, don't we?
- 是的   - 我们知道他们说的是错的, 是不?
Well, yes, it was Ogrons.
嗯, 是的, 是 Ogrons 干的
Oh, we also know that the Ogrons couldn't possibly
我们也知道 Ogrons 不太可能
have created that hallucinatory device
能制造出那种致幻设备
that makes the Earthmen think they're Draconians.
可以让地球人产生错觉, 以为是龙族人袭击了他们
Oh. Oh, well, that's simple then.
哦, 哦, 这样就简单了
I mean, what we've got to is find out what's going on,
我是说, 我们要做的, 就是搞明白到底是怎么一回事
who's behind the Ogrons, where they've taken the TARDIS,
谁在操纵这些 Ogrons, 他们又把 TARDIS 带到哪里去了
go and get it back and then we can all go home.
我们去把它找回来, 然后我们就可以回家了
- Right? - Right.
- 对吧?  - 对
Oh. I don't know what I've been worrying about.
哦, 我不知道一直在担心什么
We are now in space port 10.
我们正在十号太空站
The ship will land in 15 minutes. The crew are safe.
飞船将在15分钟内降落, 船员都安全
Also aboard, two human stowaways, origins unknown.
船上还有两个偷渡的人类, 来源未知
I want a cordon around the landing area,
the minute that ship touches down.
我需要飞船一着地, 就在周边拉起警戒线
Nobody on, nobody off till I get there.
在我到达之前, 任何人不得进入, 任何人不得离开
Sir.
先生
I'd better get down there.
I want handle the preliminary interrogations myself.
我最好还是下去, 我想亲自进行初步的审讯
- Outside. - We want to see somebody in authority.
- 出来 - 我们要见你们老大
You're going to, but outside.
你会见到的, 不过得先出来
Now then, what's all this about?
既然这样, 这些又什么意思
- Draconian agents? Are you sure? - What else can they be?
- 龙族特工? 你确定吗?   - 要不然还能是什么
Their story is obvious nonsense.
他们的故事显然说不通啊
But why? We...
为什么? 我们...
Why would the Draconians leave them on board the ship?
为什么龙族人会把他们继续留在飞船上?
The Draconians are preparing for war.
那些龙族人正在准备一场战争
You're still only suspecting that. There is no proof.
你这只是在怀疑, 但没有证据
Then they need to plant human agents,
所以他们需要安插两名人类特工
traitors, on this planet to sabotage our war effort.
两个叛徒, 好让他们在这个星球上破坏我们的反击
But we are bound to suspect them. They must have realised.
但我们肯定会怀疑他们啊, 他们肯定能想到这个
The Draconians probably thought the crew was dead.
那些龙族人也许认为船员都死了
We could easily have accepted those two as passengers,
以为我们会轻易地相信这两个家伙真的是乘客
two unfortunate refugees from a Draconian attack,
是两个躲避龙族人袭击的不幸难民
- When did you last eat? - Quite some while ago.
- 你上次什么时候吃饭的? - 有些时候了
Well, I'll see they send you some food.
好吧, 我去让他们给你们送点食物进来
I'd like to get a message through to your president.
我期望给你们的总统带个信息
Not a chance.
别妄想了
I'm going straight back to my ship.
我就直接回我的船了
Don't want to get mixed up with security.
别想着破坏这里的安保设施
It's not healthy.
这对你不好
- Look, I'll give you a piece of advice. - DOCTOR: Yes?
- 对了, 我要给你们一个小建议 - 什么...
Sooner or later, you're going to tell them everything.
或早或迟, 你们都给告诉他们全部实情
They'll use the mind probe. You talk to them now.
他们会使用思维探测器的, 你们还是现在就说实话吧
You'll save yourselves a lot of trouble.
这也可以给你们自己省去很多麻烦
PRESIDENT: And you are quite sure it was a Draconian battle cruiser.
你确定那是一艘龙族战斗巡航舰吗?
Of course, Madam.
当然, 夫人
They locked on and boarded us.
他们锁定了我们, 强行登了船
We saw them. They were Draconians.
我们都看见了, 他们是龙族人
Thank you. That will be all.
谢谢你, 你们可以走了
I hope you will soon recover from your ordeal.
期望你很快从这些磨难中恢复过来
Well, Your Highness?
怎样, 殿下?
These men are your servants.
他们都是你的人
They are saying what they have been ordered to say.
你们让他们说什么, 他们就说什么
On this occasion, we have more than our servants to confront you with.
这次不同了, 能跟你对质的不仅仅是我们的人
We have captured two of your human agents.
我们抓住了你的两个人类间谍
We have no human agents.
我们没有人类间谍
Subversion and espionage are expressly forbidden
破坏与间谍活动是明令禁止的
by the treaty of peace between our two empires.
我们两国的和平条约已经写得很清楚了
A treaty which you have flagrantly broken.
这个条约已经被你们戳得千疮百孔了
I shall return to my embassy.
我回大使馆了
Just a moment please, Your Highness. Bring them in.
请等一下, 殿下. 把他们带进来
These people stowed away on the cargo ship.
这两个人偷渡在那艘货船上
They transmitted signals
他们往外面发信号
which enabled your battle cruiser to home in on its prey.
引导你们的战斗巡航舰过来实施攻击
I know nothing of this.
我对此毫不知情
Perhaps you do not, but some servant of the Draconian empire employed them.
也许你是不知道, 但龙族帝国的某些人雇佣了他们
Madam, I can assure that I've never been employed by anybody.
夫人, 我可以保证, 我从来没有被任何人雇佣
Least of all by the Draconians.
更别说被龙族人雇佣了
Your servants should have been better rehearsed in their lies.
你的喽罗应该好好排练一下如何撒谎
Or they're showing a misguided loyalty to their Draconian masters.
或许他们只是对龙族主人展现了错误的忠诚 (fixme)
If we really were working for the Draconians,
如果我们真的是在为龙族人办事
why did they leave us in your ship?
他们怎么会把我们留在你们的船上
To act as spies when you were brought back to Earth.
为了方便你们被带回地球之后可以继续充当间谍
Allow me to congratulate you, sir.
请允许我祝贺你, 先生
You have the most totally closed mind that I've ever encountered.
你拥有我所见过的最封闭的头脑
Madam, I beg of you to listen to me.
夫人, 我请求你能听我说
Some third party is trying to provoke war between Earth and Draconia.
某个第三方团体正试图挑起地球与龙族的战争
You are both being duped.
你们两边都被欺骗了
Take them away.
把他们带走
Just a minute, please.
请等一下
Why should a third party wish to do this?
为什么某个第三方团体想干这个
I've no idea, Madam,
我不知道, 夫人
but believe me, that is what is happening.
但相信我, 这就是真相
Take them away.
把他们带走
Now please listen to me! If you don't
现在请听我说! 如果你不听的话
you'll be involved in a war that could cause the death of millions.
你们就会卷入一场战争, 百万生灵将因此丧命
Is this the evidence upon which you accuse me?
这就是你们控诉我的证据?
I must ask you to convey a formal protest to your Emperor.
我必须要求你向你的皇帝转达我们的正式抗议
I shall inform him of this latest insult
to the honour of the Draconian empire.
我会告诉他的, 告诉他你们对龙族尊严的侮辱
But why?
不过为什么?
Why should they produce such an elaborate lie?
为什么要编造一个如此复杂的谎言
The ways of the Earthmen are devious. They're an inscrutable species.
地球人的行为很怪异, 他们这个种族真是难以揣测
Obviously, they are preparing the next stage of their plan.
很显然, 他们在为他们自己计划的下一步铺路
First, the attacks on our ships and now this.
首先, 攻击我们的船, 然后又是这个
Is it possible, Your Highness,
that for once the Earthmen spoke the truth?
有没有可能, 殿下, 这一次地球人说的是事实?
Some plan of the Emperor of which Your Highness has not been informed?
皇帝有他自己的计划, 而没有告知殿下?
The Emperor would not possibly contemplate such a plan.
我们的皇帝不会弄出这样的计划
We do not break the treaty of peace.
我们不能打破和平协定
Shall I prepare your Excellency's report
to the Emperor on this meeting?
我可以去准备报告了吗, 您觐见皇帝陛下时的报告
I must have more information.
我必须获得更多的信息
It would be useful to question the humans who were found on the ship.
如果能审讯一下船上找到的那两个人, 应该会有帮助
They are supposed to be prisoners.
他们肯定被囚禁起来了
Prisoners have been known to escape, Your Highness.
被囚禁的人都是可以逃走的, 殿下
Not without help.
那得有人帮忙才行
And that would be a grave act of hostility.
而这可是严重的敌对行为
I could not possibly countenance such a plan.
我不可能支持这样的计划
But, should two escaping prisoners seek sanctuary in this embassy,
但是, 如果两个逃犯到大使馆来寻求庇护
it would be uncivilised to turn them away.
我们弃而不管就太不人道了
I must not detain you longer.
我就不再耽搁你了
No doubt you have duties demanding your attention?
无疑你现在还有更需要你关注的事情?
Your Highness.
殿下